A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 13949-17726 FA739F
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Brazil trip report: Nutrition program (Reports 016361), 1975 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  Trip made to Brazil by Sol Chafkin from May 16 - 23, 1975 concerning the nutrition program.
  07100328
  Nutrition -- Brazil; Agricultural development projects -- Brazil
- Series of reports on Educational Planning and Research Division, Malaysia (Reports 016362), 1973 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  Three quarterly reports and one year end report by Bob Cleary for the Educational Planning and Research Division in Malaysia.
  Asia and the Pacific/International Division
  06990191
  Education -- Malaysia
- Organizations formerly dependent on the Ford Foundation for which support has been discontinued 197? (Reports 016363), undated (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  List of grantees funded by the Ford Foundation
  Finance
  Endowments -- Finance; Philanthropy -- Finance
- Thoughts on the "National Perspective" on international relations, December 9 (Reports 016364), 1976 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  Inter-office memo from Richard Fagan to Robert Drysdale dated December 9, 1976.
  07750395
- CONICET matching fund grant for agricultural economics research in Argentina 9720 - 0128): Michigan State University, April 5 (Reports 016365), 1974 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  Memo from Darrell F. Fienup to Peter Bell and Peter Hakim.
  07200128
  Agricultural development projects -- Latin America; Economics
- Educational Planning and Research Division (EPRD): terminal evaluation (Reports 016366), 1978 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  "Terminal evaluation of Ford Foundation support to Educational Planning & Research Division (EPRD), Malaysia." (p.1)
- Los Angeles visit, July 30 (Reports 016367), 1992 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  Riots -- Social aspects -- California -- Los Angeles (Calif.); Urban policy -- California -- Los Angeles (Calif.); Endowments -- California -- Los Angeles (Calif.); Philanthropy -- California -- Los Angeles (Calif.)
- Southern Languages Book Trust: An evaluation of its record between 1955 and (Reports 016368), 1970 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  Second comprehensive evaluation of Southern Languages Book Trust.
  05500205
  Publishers and publishing -- India
- Monitoring report: Home Advisory and Service Council (Reports 016369), 1973 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  Final report
  Government and Law
  06800093
  Legal aid; Probation; Court system family counseling
- Series of monthly reports on the Educational Planning and Research Division, Malaysia, August 1969 through (Reports 016370), 1971 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  Series of monthly reports from Robert W. McMeekin to John P. Kennedy spanning the years of 1969 to 1971.
  EPRD monthly reports
- International Commission of Jurists Seminar on "human rights in rural areas of the Andean Region" (Reports 016371), 1979 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  Inter-office memo from Jan Flora and Robert Myers to Richard W. Dye dated November 5, 1979.[…]Narrative report of 9/79.
  Education -- Congresses
- Staff development memos and papers prepared while at the Ford Foundation as a project specialist with EPP (Reports 016372), 1976 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  07390811
  Teacher educators; Schools -- Staff development; Staff development -- Education
- The college teaching program at Goucher College: report on visit of 5/2-3/ (Reports 016373), 1966 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  1966 site visit report on the College Teaching Program at Goucher College.
  06300281
  Education, Higher; Teachers -- Training of -- Goucher College
- Southeast Asian regional cooperation in population planning (Reports 016374), 1970 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  International Division/Population Program
  06890147
  Population policy -- Southeast Asia
- Review of National Nutrition Survey, Chile (Reports 016375), 1974 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  07200445
  Nutrition -- Chile; Agricultural development projects -- Chile
- Visit to the Instituto Tecnologico University of Oriente: Puerta La Cruz, February 14 (Reports 016376), 1968 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  Site visit report on the Instituto Tecnologico University of Oriente (Universidad de Oriente) in Puerta La Cruz
  Overseas Division/Latin America;International Division/Latin America
  University Of Oriente
  Education, Higher; Universidad de Oriente (Puerto la Cruz)
- Rural Teacher Training College (Lebanon): report and various memos, December 1957 to (Reports 016377), 1958 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  This is a series of six documents and letters produced by Louis Smith from December 9, 1957 through March 13, 1958 concerning the Lebanon Ministry of Education and the Rural Teacher Training College (Lebanon).
  Overseas Division/Near East and Africa
  05600318
  Teachers -- Training of -- Lebanon; Teacher Training Centers -- Lebanon; Education, Higher -- Lebanon
- Ford Foundation New Delhi office evaluation reports on the Intensive Agricultural District Programme (IADP) (Reports 016378), 1975 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  This is a series of two reports attached to an inter-office memo from the New Delhi office concerning the evaluation of the Intensive Agricultural District Program (IADP)
  06100080
  Agricultural development projects -- India
- Southern Police Institute at the University of Louisville (Reports 016379), 1969 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  This is a series of inter-office two memos written by Clayton Willis to Christopher F. Edley concerning the University of Louisville and the Southern Police Institute dated May 12, 1969 and April 21, 1969.[…]Retained in this grant on Microfilm.
  06000174
  Education -- Police; Police training; Police -- Study and teaching
- Institute for Cultural Enterprise: Documents and materials (Reports 016380), 2001 (Box 840, Reel R-9317)
  Incorporation documents for the establishment of the Institute for Cultural Enterprise.[…]Documentation includes incorporating statements and articles, employer identification numbers, board minutes, grant details, tax information, and insurance papers.
  Nonprofit organizations -- Office management; New business enterprises; Arts administrators; Trusts and trustees
- World Cultural Forum: transcripts, meeting June 26-27 (Reports 016381), 2001 (Box 841, Reel R-9318)
  Culture
- World Culture Forum, Institute for Cultural Enterprise: papers and correspondence (Reports 016382), 2002 (Box 841, Reel R-9318)
  Damien Pwono (FF);Franz Patay (not FF);Margaret Wilkerson (FF);Milagros Del Corral (UNESCO);Danny Yung (not FF);Susan K. Stevens (consultant)
  World Culture Forum
  Cross-cultural studies; Cultural relations
- A structural assessment of the Institute for Cultural Enterprise and the World Culture Forum confidential report to the Ford Foundation, April 28 (Reports 016383), 2002 (Box 841, Reel R-9318)
  Consultant report on the Ford Foundation's proposed role in the World Culture Forum and its continued support of the Institute for Cultural Enterprise.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Office management; Endowments -- Program-related investments; Forums (Discussion and debate)
- Institute for Cultural Enterprise and World Culture Forum: structural assessment and summary report, May 1 (Reports 016384), 2002 (Box 841, Reel R-9318)
- Institute for Cultural Enterprise (ICE): knowledge building activities (Reports 016385), 2002 (Box 841, Reel R-9318)
  Grant report to the Ford Foundation
  10001348
  New York Foundation for the Arts, Inc.
  Art, African -- 20th century; Dance -- Africa; Arts -- Africa; Healing -- Hawaii; Hawaiians -- Medicine
- Excellence through diversity: profiles of forty-two Ford Foundation Fellows (Reports 016386), 1996 (Box 841, Reel R-9318)
  Minorities -- Scholarships, fellowships, etc.; Scholarships
- Comments by Susan V. Berresford at the opening of the 1997 directors and representatives meeting, February 21 (Reports 016387) (Box 841, Reel R-9318)
  Comments prepared by Susan Berresford and presented to the directors and representatives meeting of February 21, 1997.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Congresses
- Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom program: Retreat 2003, September 30 - October 1 (Reports 016388) (Box 841, Reel R-9318)
  Annual retreat documents for the Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom program, held at Harrison Conference Center, Glen Cove, NY, September 30 through October 1, 2003.
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Office management; Management retreats
- Strategies for rural development and increased access to education: a toolkit for rural community colleges (Reports 016389), 1998 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  Rural community development -- United States; Community colleges -- United States; Rural development -- United States
- Budapest trip notes (Reports 016390), 1990 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  Human rights -- Europe, Eastern
- Visit to Budapest and Vienna, January 19 (Reports 016391), 1990 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
- The Ford Foundation investment report: Investment committee meeting (Reports 016392), 2004 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  "Confidential, for internal circulation only."
  Ford Foundation. Investment Committee Meeting (2004: New York, NY)
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- Office management -- Congresses; Nonprofit organizations -- Finance -- Congresses
- Economics and the Ford Foundation: an historical perspective (Reports 016393), undated (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  Economic history
- Soviet and East European study group interim report for discussion at the board meeting on December 8 (Reports 016394), 1988 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  The following is an interim report on the work to date of a Study Group that was formed in June 1988 to examine how the Foundation might best respond to recent changes in the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe.--P. 1
  Political science -- Soviet Union; Political science -- Europe, Eastern; International relations; International cooperation
- Equal access to knowledge for the children of the poor (POM) (Reports 016395), 2004 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  The overall goal of this portfolio is to foster equal access to knowledge for the most vulnerable and underserved students in this region- the children of the poor and indigenous populations.--P. 1
  Education -- Latin America; Educational equalization -- Latin America
- Spaces for creative encounter and expression and scholarship for the future (POM) (Reports 016396), 2004 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  "The two initiatives outlined in this Program Officer's Memo focus on issues of identity, representation and space both as a means of addressing difficult issues of social change and as a means of linking grant making across the fields of Arts and Culture
  Education -- Vietnam
- Why not organize?: the role of community organizing in the Ford Foundation Economic Development Unit (Reports 016397), 2004 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  This report examines the role of community organizing in the programming of the Ford Foundation's Economic Development unit (EDU).--P. 1
  Community organization
- Annual report 1964 (Reports 016398), 1975
  Technical assistance -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Africa; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Africa -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- Middle East; Philanthropy -- Africa -- 1964-1975; Ford Foundation
- Middle East - Africa program summary report at end of fiscal year (Reports 016398-001), 1964 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  Technical assistance -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Africa; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Africa -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- Middle East; Philanthropy -- Africa -- 1964-1975
- Office for Middle East and Africa annual report - fiscal (Reports 016398-002), 1968 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  Technical assistance -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Africa; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Africa -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- Middle East; Philanthropy -- Africa -- 1964-1976
- Office for Middle East and Africa annual report - fiscal (Reports 016398-003), 1969 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  Technical assistance -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Africa; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Africa -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- Middle East; Philanthropy -- Africa -- 1964-1977
- Middle East and Africa: 1970 annual report (Reports 016398-004), 1971 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  Technical assistance -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Africa; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Africa -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- Middle East; Philanthropy -- Africa -- 1964-1978
- Middle East and Africa: 1970 annual report (Reports 016398-005), 1971 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  Technical assistance -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Africa; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Africa -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- Middle East; Philanthropy -- Africa -- 1964-1979
- Office for Middle East and Africa: Annual report (Reports 016398-006), 1974 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  Technical assistance -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Africa; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Africa -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- Middle East; Philanthropy -- Africa -- 1964-1980
- Office for the Middle East and Africa: Annual report fiscal year (Reports 016398-007), 1976 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  Technical assistance -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Africa; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Africa -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- Middle East; Philanthropy -- Africa -- 1964-1981
- Office for the Middle East and Africa: Annual report fiscal year (Reports 016398-008), 1975 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  Technical assistance -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Africa; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Africa -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- Middle East; Philanthropy -- Africa -- 1964-1982
- Memorandum on role of Ford Foundation in educational television (Reports 016399), 1962 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  Television in education -- United States -- Finance; Educational television stations -- United States -- Finance; Public broadcasting -- United States -- Finance
- Women's pathways to public leadership: Profile (Reports 016400), 1998 (Box 842, Reel R-9318)
  Leadership; Women executives; Women in development
- The Ford Foundation: India, Nepal and Sri Lanka: Statement of current interests, 2000 (Reports 016401) (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  Well-illustrated program brochure outlining the Ford Foundation's presence in India, Nepal and Sri Lanka, with brief history of the Foundation and details of the program work in the areas human rights, reproductive health, economic and community developme
  Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- India; Human rights -- India; Reproductive health -- India; Economic development -- India; Arts -- India; Environmental responsibility -- India
- At a glance: building social capacity through faith-based initiatives (Reports 016402), 1998 (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  Community development -- Religious aspects
- Youth leadership for development initiative: Broadening the parameters of youth development and strengthening civic activism (Reports 016403), 1998 (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  09951042
  National 4-H Council
  Civil society -- Citizen participation; Youth development
- Innovations in American government 1999: an awards program of the Ford Foundation administered by the John F. Kennedy School of Government at Harvard University in partnership with the Council for Excellence in Government (Reports 016404) (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  Yearly report on the recipients of Innovations in American Government Awards. […]Yearly report on the recipients of Innovations in American Government Awards.
  Innovations in American government
  State governments -- United States -- Awards; Local government -- United States -- Awards; Federal government -- United States -- Awards
- The International Youth Development Exchange 1998-9: an evaluation of the Kenyan experience (Reports 016405), 1999 (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  ii, 65 p.: col. ill. -- 30 cm.
  Youth development -- Kenya
- Participatory rural appraisal: Proceedings of the February 1991 Bangalore PRA trainers workshop: RRA notes number 13 (Reports 016406) (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  09001509
  RRA notes
  Rural development -- India -- Citizen participation; Social action -- India; Community development -- India -- Citizen participation
- Rowing upstream: snapshots of pioneers of the information age in Africa (Reports 016407), 2002 (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  09990006
  xii, 126 p.: col ill., col. maps -- 30 cm. + 1 CD-ROM (4 3/4 in.)
  Information technology -- Africa; Internet -- Africa; Computer networks -- Africa
- Ford Foundation project on development of data bank on growth and physical development of Indian children and studies on the changing pattern of growth: draft report (Reports 016408), 1991 (Box 901, Reel R-9318)
  From Forward written by (Padam Singh), Director: "The Institute for Research in Medical Statistics (IRMS), Delhi chapter, has taken initiative to establish Data Bank on topics of research in various aspects of health and to begin with, decision was taken[…]"The data collected through systematic studies (surveys, experiments, research services etc.) in the field of bio-medical sciences from different regions and population groups of the country over a period of time since Independence and maintained upto-dat
  Growth and physical development of Indian children: draft report
  Children -- India -- Growth -- Statistics; Child development -- India -- Statistics; Children -- Anthropometry -- India
- Religion seminar: transcription of a talk by Abdullahi An-Na'im given on February 10 (Reports 016409), 2000 (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  "...[W]ith clear appreciation of the reasons for the political and social reality of tension between human rights, religion and secularism, I will argue for synergy and interdependence of these three paradigms, rather than a choice between them. By synerg
  Human rights -- Religious aspects; Secularism; Islam and secularism; Religion -- Workshops, seminars, symposia
- Religion seminar: transcription of a talk by Diana L. Eck given on December 4 (Reports 016410), 2001 (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  "I want to tell you a little bit about the Bozeman to Banaras trajectory, because I think it actually says a good bit about my own career. I started as a scholar of religion in South Asia ... and yet I never imagined when I started studying India in the 1
  Religion -- Workshops, seminars, symposia; Religious pluralism
- Report on visit to Brazil, April 1-12 (Reports 016411), 1996 (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  Reproductive health -- Brazil; Social sciences and ethics -- Brazil; Social sciences -- Research -- Brazil; Endowments -- Brazil
- Recommendations and insights for a pending initiative on teacher quality: an internal report to the Ford Foundation, May 24 (Reports 016412), 2004 (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  Report of a project investigating in the area of teacher quality. Teacher quality refers to all activities that build the capacity of teachers and the teaching sector.
  Teachers -- Training of; Teaching -- Research; Teachers -- Job satisfaction; Activity programs in education
- A review of the Ford Foundation grantmaking portfolio on teacher quality, September 16 (Reports 016413), 2003 (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  Review of the teacher quality component of the portfolio held by Joseph Aguerrebere. The purposes of the review were to provide an overview of the portfolio and patterns of grantmaking, to make some assessment of the impact of the grants, and to identify
  Teachers -- Training of; Academic achievement; Education -- United States
- Ford Foundation Report (Reports 016414), 2003 (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  Report addressing the Ford Foundation's involvement with education and preparation for teachers in urban areas.
  Teachers -- Training of; Education, Urban
- Developing Country Programs: FY 1988 program reviews: rapporteur notes, October 21-30 (Reports 016415), 1987 (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  Technical assistance -- Developing countries
- Roy Wilkins anthology, June/ (Reports 016416), 1977 (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  Special issue of The Crisis in honor of Roy Wilkins, vol. 84, no. 6 (743), June/July 1977, including a compilation of Wilkins' speeches and writings for the magazine.
  342 p. -- 28 cm.
  Crisis
  African Americans -- Social conditions; African Americans -- Civil rights
- Staff papers for Trustees Planning Project on Liberal Tradition, 1976. (Reports 016417) (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  In addition to the 9 items, there is a memo from Richard S. Sharpe to Foundation staff that accompanied copies of the papers as they were distributed to staff members. The papers cover a range of topics including the study of social justice, the arts, int
  PAPER Conference (1976 Oct. 28: New York, N.Y.)
- Staff papers for Trustees Planning Project on International Activities, 1976. (Reports 016418) (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  In addition to the 7 items, there is a memo from Richard S. Sharpe to Foundation staff that accompanied copies of the papers as they were distributed to staff members. The topics presented in these papers include supporting research for population control
  International relations and culture; Developing countries; Humanitarianism; International Affairs program
- Understanding and combating anti-Semitism in Europe: observations prepared for convening on May 12, 2004 in Brussels, May 12 (Reports 016419) (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  This paper serves as a starting point for a discussion which will help the Ford Foundation to establish a program to combat antisemitism and racism in Europe. (p.1)
  Understanding and combating anti-Semitism in Europe (2004 May 12: Brussels)
  Antisemitism -- Europe -- Congresses; Religious tolerance -- International cooperation -- Congresses
- Ford Foundation: agenda book: program officer orientation, September 19-30 (Reports 016420), 1994 (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  This is the agenda book for program officer orientation on September 19-30, 1994
  Employee induction -- Congresses; Philanthropy -- Study and teaching -- Congresses
- The 21st century NGO: in the market for change (Reports 016421), 2003 (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  Provides an overview of what non-governmental organizations are and presents issues of governance, partnerships with corporations, finance, accountability and market influence.
  twenty-first century ngo;twentyfirst century ngo
  Non-governmental organizations; Civil society; Social responsibility of business
- Memorandum: confidential report and recommendations regarding the Ford Project, August 15 (Reports 016422), 1968 (Box 843, Reel R-9318)
  The following is intended as a confidential report and recommendations from the Communications Analyst and Field Director to the Director of the Office of Communication regarding the Ford Project.-- P. [1]
  06800203
  United Church of Christ
  Discrimination in employment; Minorities -- Employment; Minorities in the television industry -- Minorities in broadcasting
- A Program to combat racial discrimination in broadcasting: an interim report submitted to the Ford Foundation pursuant to the terms on grant number 68-203, November 7 (Reports 016423), 1969 (Box 844, Reel R-9318)
  "The following report covers the activities of the Office of Communication of the United Church of Christ in its program to combat racial discrimination in broadcasting funded under Ford Foundation Grant no. 68-203 from February 1 through September 30, 19
  Discrimination in employment; Minorities -- Employment; Minorities in the television industry; Minorities in broadcasting
- A Program to combat racial discrimination on broadcasting: an interim report of activities under Ford Foundation grant number 680-0203D, May 28 (Reports 016424), 1973 (Box 844, Reel R-9318)